RG 074:007, George McKenzie Roberts Genealogical Papers
Connecticut State Library
George McKenzie Roberts genealogical papers
1851-1964
bulk 1956-1960
Connecticut State Library
Roberts, George McKenzie
1.5 cubic feet
George McKenzie Roberts (1886-1980) was elected a Fellow of the American Society of Genealogists in 1950. These papers include manuscript drafts of genealogies of the John Roberts, Andrew Smith, Ebenezer Spear, and Abel and Elizabeth (Spear) Wellington families.
RG074_007
1960-002
Biographical Note
George McKenzie Roberts was born on December 28, 1886 at Vergennes, Vermont to George Simon and Florence Louise (McKenzie) Roberts. He married twice, to Anne Edith Campbell on October 20, 1909 at New Haven, and to Grace Agnes (Rhodes) Perkins on November 22, 1943 at Reno. It is believed that both marriages ended in divorce. There were no children. Roberts died on April 7, 1980 at San Francisco, California.
Roberts was educated only to the eighth or ninth grade. He began employment with General Electric in 1901. From 1919 to 1953 he worked for the International General Electric Company, Inc. in New York City as Credit Manager, Assistant Treasurer, and Treasurer. He was also Treasurer and a Director of Electrical Export Corporation. He was Chief of the Foreign Trade Branch, U.S. Office of Price Stabilization, Washington, D.C. from 1951 until his retirement in 1953. He was a director of the New York Board of Trade and of other business clubs and associations from 1920 to 1950.
Although Roberts did not publish any books, he published two genealogies that ran serially in the New York Genealogical and Biographical Record: "The Druse Genealogy," in 1938-1939, and "The Denslow Family in America," from 1946-1950 and 1957-1959. He produced a series of vital records, cemetery records, land and tax records, probate records, census enumerations, and Revolutionary soldiers' records, all relating to the town of Enfield, New Hampshire, in the N.Y.G. & B. Record in 1957. He also published and article, "On the Marring of Research Sources," in The American Genealogist in October 1955. He published his Ancestor Table in that same issue.
Roberts was elected a Fellow of The American Society of Genealogists in 1950. He also belonged to the New England Historic Genealogical Society, the New York Genealogical and Biographical Society, the S.A. R., for which he served as Treasurer General and Genealogist General, Society of Colonial Wars in the State of New York, New York State Historical Association, Vermont, New Hampshire and Connecticut Historical Societies, Descendants of the Illegitimate Sons and Daughters of the Kings of Britain, Denslow Family Association, and others.
Source: Newsletter of the American Society of Genealogists 39.1 (January 1981): 3-4.
Scope and Content
These papers contain manuscript drafts of the following genealogies: John Roberts, 1751-1834, of Hartford, Conn.: his family and descendants; Andrew Smith, 1779-1819 of Hartford, Conn.: his family and descendants; Ebenezer Spear, 1762-1826 of Hartford, Conn.: his family and descendants; and Abel, 1789-1875 & Elizabeth (Spear), 1793-1875, Wellington of Bethel, Vermont: their family and descendants. The Roberts and Smith genealogies are accompanied by correspondence and other material accumulated by Roberts while gathering genealogical data. These files are arranged by correspondent. Also present are genealogical records about the Roberts, Smith and Spear Families divided into cemetery, estate, and vital records. These files contain some photocopies of original estate papers, and death and marriage certificates. Finally, there are a few notecards relating to the Denslow genealogy, but there are no other papers related to that project.
Related Material
Roberts, Robards, Robbards, Robbarts, Robberds, Robberts, Robords family: History and Genealogy Unit Special Genealogical File, 1816-1989
Smith family: History and Genealogy Unit Special Genealogical File, 1802-2001
Spear family: History and Genealogy Unit Special Genealogical File, 1834-1969
Index Terms
Persons:
Roberts, George McKenzie
Family Names:
Roberts family; Smith family; Spears family; Wellington family
Places:
Bethel (Vt.) -- Genealogy; Hartford (Conn.) -- Genealogy; New Hampshire -- Genealogy
Subjects:
Roberts, John, 1751-1834 -- Family; Smith, Andrew, 1779-1819 -- Family; Spear, Ebenezer, 1762-1826 -- Family; Wellington, Abel, 1789-1875 -- Family; Wellington, Elizabeth Spear, 1793-1875 -- Family
Document Types:
Correspondence; Death certificates; Estate records; Genealogies; Marriage certificates
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Acquisition Information
George McKenzie roberts presented these papers to the Connecticut State Library in 1960. The notecards on the Denslow Family were added afterwards.
Container List
- John Roberts, 1751-1834, of Hartford, Conn.: his family and descendants, 1956-1960
  - Manuscript draft, 1960 (Box 1)
    An abridged version is available at. Researchers should also consult the manuscript draft for additional information.
  - Correspondence and other material, 1956-1960 (Box 1)
    - Baker; Blanco, 1956-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Allen; Brewer, Charles Crawford; Brewer, Louise H.; Brewer, N. Howard; Brewer, Norman W., 1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Brewer, Robert Selden; Brewer, Vincent C., 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Cox; Hamlin; Shamel, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Welling; Wickham; Chaffin, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Church Street property; Dix, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Hubbard; Jepson; Lawton, Frank, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Lawton, Harry A., 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Military & pension; Peck, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Pierce; Roberts, Edmund Donald, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Roberts, George Simon; Roberts, Henry A.; Roberts, Robert; Roberts, Robert C.; Roberts, Stanley, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Roberts, Mary E.; Sanford, 1956, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Spencer, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Sperry, 1956-1958 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Universalist Church of the Redeemer, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Andrew Smith, 1779-1819 of Hartford, Conn.: his family and descendants, 1917-1960; bulk 1956-1960
  - Manuscript draft, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and other material, 1917-1958, bulk 1956-1958 (Box 2)
    - Adamson; Broili; Chapin, 1926,1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Clark; Gaylord; Gould, 1956-1958 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Ingerman; Lederer, 1956-1958 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Leonard, Franklin C., 1957 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - MacGregor, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Mills; Schryver; Smith, Charles Gilbert, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Smith, Edwin B.; Smith, Edwin W.; Smith, Ernest A., 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Smith, James Metcalf; Smith, Mary Ann, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Smith, Stanley K., 1954-1958 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Smith, William T.; Winne; Westfield, Mass.; Westfield Athenaeum, 1917, 1956-1958 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Ebenezer Spear, 1762-1826 of Hartford, Conn.: his family and descendants, 1960
  - Manuscript draft, 1960 (Box 3)
- Abel, 1789-1875 & Elizabeth (Spear), 1793-1875, Wellington of Bethel, Vermont: their family and descendants, 1962, undated
  - First manuscript draft, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Second manuscript draft, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Another version is available at. Researchers should also consult the manuscript drafts for variations.
- Genealogical records pertaining to the Roberts, Smith and Spear Families, 1851-1959; bulk 1956-1959
  - Cemeteries, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Estates, 1868-1923, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Includes photocopies of estate papers.
  - Vital records, 1851-1959 (Box 3, Folder 5-9)
    Includes photocopies of death and marriage certificates.
- Notecards on Denslow Family, 1963-1964
  - Notecards, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)